gortons.com 2001-06-02

# Unilever Privacy Policy

**Unilever United States, Inc. Privacy Policy**

The web site you have entered is operated by or on behalf of a subsidiary of Unilever United States, Inc., which is a member of the Unilever group of companies ("Unilever"). 

Unilever is committed to protecting your personal privacy. This Privacy Policy outlines the type of information that is collected by Unilever on this web site, and how we use and protect it. This Policy also tells you what to do if you do not want your Personal Information collected when you visit our web site, and how you can change information you have already provided to us.  This Policy applies only to the Unilever web sites listed here.  For example, it does not apply to banners, sweepstakes and other advertisements or promotions we may sponsor or participate in on web sites owned by third parties. 

For specific information regarding the privacy of children who visit our sites, click here. 

**Your Consent to This Privacy Policy**

By using our web site, you signify that you agree with the terms of our current Privacy Policy as posted in this area of the site. If you do not agree with any term in this Policy, please do not provide any Personal Information (defined below) on this site. 

If you choose not to provide Personal Information on this site, you may not be able to do certain things, like access particular areas of the site, enter a sweepstakes or contest, request samples, or send us e-mail. 

**Collection of Personal Information**

As used in this Privacy Policy, "Personal Information" means personally identifiable information such as your name, street address, telephone number, credit card information, screen name and email address.  The site you entered may collect some or all of these types of Personal Information.  Please be assured that Unilever will not collect any Personal Information from your visits to our sites unless you provide this information voluntarily. 

When you provide us with Personal Information, you are authorizing us to use that information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy, which includes your right to limit our use of the Personal Information as described in this Policy (see "Who to Contact" below). 

The site you entered may also collect Personal Information from you about a third party (e.g., the site might allow you to send an electronic "post card" to a friend, in which case we will need that person's name and e-mail address).  Please note that we use such information only for the specified purpose (e.g., to mail the post card) and we will not contact the third party again by e-mail unless and until the third party contacts us. 

**How We Use Your Information**

When you supply Personal Information at this web site, the brand whose site you entered will use it for the express purpose for which it was collected (e.g., to enter you in a sweepstakes or to send you a sample).  It may also be used by the brand whose site you entered, as well as by our other brands,  to contact you regarding other products and services which may be of interest to you (including those we may offer jointly with other companies).  (For more information on Unilever and its brands, see the paragraph about Unilever at the end of this Policy.)  At any time, however, you may opt out of such future contact. (See "Who to Contact" below.) 

At times we may retain third parties to analyze data we collect on our web sites, including Personal Information, solely to help us improve our products and our web sites.  In addition, if you order a product or service from us, we may share Personal Information with suppliers and other third parties to allow delivery of such product or service.  These suppliers and other third parties are not authorized by us to use your Personal Information in any other way. 

Finally, please note that we will release your Personal Information if required to do so by law, or by search warrant, subpoena or court order. 

**Other Information We May Collect**

You may have heard of "cookies," which are files or pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive.  Unilever may use cookies to collect other information during your visit to our web site, such as the particular site areas you visit and the products or services you buy through our web site. We collect this information to better tailor our site and our products to your interests and needs. Cookies may also be used to help speed up your future activities at our site; the computer can remember that you have already provided Personal Information to us and not request that you provide any a second time. 

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you'd prefer, you can set yours to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent.  Refusal of cookies at the site you entered may result in an inability to visit certain areas of the site or to receive personalized information when you visit the site. 

In addition, we are constantly trying to improve how we promote our web sites. To help us do this, we may measure the effectiveness of our web presence by determining what you clicked on to get to our site. 

Information about your computer, such as your IP address (a number assigned to your computer whenever you surf the Internet), the type of Internet browser you are using and the type of computer operating system you are using may also be collected and linked to your Personal Information.  This is to ensure that our web sites present the best web experience for visitors, and that they are an effective information resource. 

Finally, we may supplement the information that you provided us with other information that we receive from third parties.  We do this for marketing purposes in order to provide more targeted products and service to meet your needs. 

**Children**

Unilever is committed to protecting the online privacy of children and making the Internet safe for our users. For this reason, Unilever sites which are directed in whole or in part at children or likely to attract children (for example,  "popsicle.com" and "icecreamusa.com") have their own specific privacy policy with regard to children.  For more information about this policy, click [here.](http://www.unileverus.com/privacy/policy_children.html)

At all other Unilever sites, users are told that they must be 13 years or older before sending Personal Information. Users under age 13 should not submit any Personal Information to us. 

We encourage parents of children under 13 to regularly check and monitor their children's use of e-mail and other activities on line 

**Security of Information**

We take reasonable precautions to keep your Personal Information secure.  All personally identifiable information is subject to restricted access to prevent unauthorized access, modification or misuse. 

**Changes in Our Policy**

Unilever reserves the right to change or remove this Privacy Policy at our discretion.  We will post any new policy here and we encourage you to visit this area frequently to stay informed. 

**Who to Contact**

Please write to us at [privacy.policy@unilever.com](mailto:privacy.policy@unilever.com) or at Unilever Consumer Services, 920 Sylvan Avenue, Englewood Cliffs, NJ 07632 or call us at 1-800-221-8823 if you have any comments or questions about this Privacy Policy or to report any violations of the Privacy Policy.   We will respond to you within 24 to 48 hours in most cases. For other requests, please choose among the following options: 

  * If you **don't want to be contacted** in the future or would like us to **correct or update your Personal Information** in our records, please click the appropriate button below:

  * If you would like to **correct or update Personal Information that your child** has sent us through a Unilever site which is directed at children, or if **you don't want your child to be contacted** in the future, please click the appropriate button below:

Unilever will take reasonable steps to comply with the foregoing requests. 

Again, Unilever is committed to protecting your privacy in connection with our web sites. Please do not hesitate to contact us if you have any questions, comments or concerns about this Privacy Policy.   
  
This Policy applies to the following sites: [Lipton](http://www.lipton.com/); [Lipton Brisk](http://www.liptonbrisk.com/); [Lipton T](http://www.liptont.com/); [Lipton Teabar](http://www.liptonteabar.com/);  [Lipton TeaandHealth](http://www.teaandhealth.com/);  [Wish-Bone](http://www.wish-bone.com/);  ["I Can't Believe It's Not Butter!"](http://www.tasteyoulove.com/); [Ragu](http://www.eat.com/);  [Five Brothers;](http://www.fivebrothers.com/)  [Take Control](http://www.takecontrol.com/);  [Good Humor Breyers](http://www.icecreamusa.com/);  [Gorton's](http://www.gortons.com/); [Wisk](http://www.wisk.com/);  [Dove](http://www.dove.com/);  [Finesse](http://www.helenecurtis.com/);  [Salon Selectives](http://www.helenecurtis.com/);  [Thermasilk](http://www.helenecurtis.com/);  [Unipath](http://www.unipath.com/);  [Bertolli](http://www.bertolli.com/);   [Brummel and Brown](http://www.brummelandbrown.com/);  [Seduce Your Senses](http://www.seduceyoursenses.com/);  [Country Crock](http://www.countrycrock.com/); [Helene Curtis](http://www.helenecurtis.com/);  [Taste You Love](http://www.tasteyoulove.com/);  [Lawrys](http://www.lawrys.com/);  [Mentadent](http://www.mentadent.com/);  [Ponds](http://www.ponds.com/);  [Ponds Squad](http://www.pondssquad.com/); [Recipe Secrets](http://www.recipesecrets.com/); [Slim-Fast](http://www.slimfast.com/); [Snuggle Time](http://www.snuggletime.com/);  [Clear Plan](http://www.clearplan.com/). 

* * *

Unilever is one of the world's largest consumer products companies, marketing a wide range of foods, home and personal care products. Our purpose is to meet the everyday needs of people everywhere. 

Unilever's major products in the United States, are: Lipton brewed teas and ready-to-drink tea based beverages, soups, recipe products and side dishes; Lipton BRISK ready-to-drink tea based beverages; Wish-Bone salad dressings; Lawry's seasonings, specialty sauces and salad dressings; Imperial, Promise, Country Crock, "I Can't Believe It's Not Butter!", and Brummel & Brown spreads and sprays; Take Control spreads and dressings; Ragu pasta and pizza sauces; Five Brothers premium pasta sauces; Chicken Tonight simmer sauces; Adolph's marinades and seasonings; Bertolli olive oil; Boursin cheeses; Klondike, Popsicle and Breyers ice cream products; Gorton's frozen seafood products; Slim-Fast shakes and bars; Wisk, "all" and Surf laundry detergents; Snuggle and Final Touch fabric softeners; Sunlight dish detergents; Lever 2000, Dove, Caress, Lux, Shield, Pears and Lifebouy  personal wash products;  Vaseline skin care products; Pond's skin care products; Q-tips cotton swabs and cotton balls; Mentadent, Aim, Close-up and Pepsodent oral care products; Finesse, Salon Selectives, Suave, Thermasilk, Aqua Net and Rave hair care products; Degree, Dove, Suave and Brut antiperspirants, deodorants and toiletries; Suave facial, skin and hair care products; Calvin Klein cosmetic and fragrance products; and Unipath Clear Blue Easy and Clear Plan Easy pregnancy tests, ovulation detectors and fertility monitors. 

To return to the site you were visiting, press the back button on your browser.
